<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Harper</title>
    <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Harper</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2020 Copyright Michael Harper</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikeyharper.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/about/</guid>
      <description>* {box-sizing: border-box;}/* Container for flexboxes */.row {display: flex;flex-wrap: wrap;}/* Create four equal columns */.column {flex: 2;padding: 20px;}/* Create narrower equal columns */.columnThird {flex: 1;padding: 20px;}.row2 {display: flex;}/* On screens that are 600px wide or less, make the columns stack on top of each other instead of next to each other */@media screen and (max-width: 800px) {.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Lessons from the smart home</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/lessons-from-smart-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/lessons-from-smart-home/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes joke with my wife that she is living in my smart home laboratory, and to be fair she kind of is. Almost every week, I play around with a new product or sensor, or change the way something behaves in my house. Some things have worked, others haven’t, but there is always a lesson to learn (and sometimes a wife to apologise to for annoying).
Anyway, the aim of this blog is to capture some of the top takeways I have from my experiences, and share these to hopefully help others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East/West patterns in Covid-19: validating claims of correlation</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-east-west-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-east-west-relationship/</guid>
      <description>Recent analysis came out claiming that there was evidence of a East to West pattern of Covid impacts for Europe. The purpose of this article is to provide a statistical review of the claims made, and to help provide a clearer explanation around the work.
If this article looks long and overly detailed, that is the very point. I want to explain the decisions along the way which are being made and will aim to be as objective as possible, and to do so in a way which is hopefully not too intimidating if you aren’t overly familiar with statistical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Covid-19 deaths statistics: an explainer</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-deaths-explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-deaths-explainer/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of emphasis on getting real-time data for COVID-19, and the NHS, ONS and other organisations have been pretty great at making this available. But as with any real-time datasets, there can be caveats around how to interpet them.
This post aims to give a brief overview of the data, providing some real examples of what it represents, and mostly importantly, explains how to interpret them correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why COVID positivity rates and deaths don&#39;t always correlate</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-correlation/</guid>
      <description>In the tweet thread here, Joel raises concerns around the Covid Positivity rates and the strange relationship these have with Covid deaths. Kudos to him, he put the question out for peer review, so it seemed like a great opportunity to get some analysis out!
The tweetsI wasn&#39;t going to tweet this because I cannot make sense of it. Nor can my colleagues. So, I&#39;m going to open source it and see if the wider community can verify or refute this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Neighbouring Polygons in R</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/calculating-neighbouring-polygons-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/calculating-neighbouring-polygons-in-r/</guid>
      <description>A while back on StackOverflow, I answered a question on how to produce a map which showed how many polygons away a location was from another. This blog provides an update on how this can be used, with some slight tweaks to the answer to expand on the original. A lot of this content is based around the original from Roger Bivand here.
SetupIn order to calculate neighbouring polygons, we need to form a network of nodes for the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK goes into lockdown: further Covid-19 analysis</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-19-linear-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-19-linear-graphs/</guid>
      <description>On 23rd March, the UK introduced unprecedent measures to lockdown the country in the wake of the continuing Covid-19 outbreak. This followed a week of slowly escalating measures all designed to increase the amount of social distancing and reduce the spread of the virus. This article dives into some of the statistics available for this week and provide some more context for readers going further into the crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Covid-19 With Animated, Static and Interactive Maps</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-19-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-19-maps/</guid>
      <description>AboutI have reflecting on the unprecedented week in the UK. Even this time last week, the country seemed fairly laid back as government advice was largely to continue with business as usual. It is all very different to now, with schools set to close on Monday and most people either working from home or not working at all.
This blog post provides details of anaylsis and data viusalisation to assess the spread of virus, giving three example maps which I have produced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Preliminary Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-19-march-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/covid-19-march-17/</guid>
      <description>As a data analyst, I always get happy when I discover there are great datasets available for interesting and important global events. I make a lot of my own decision making through data, and therefore this data gives me a way to cut through all the media noise which can often be present. This is certainly the case with the COVID-19 outbreak which is currently sweeping the UK media!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I learnt at rstudio::conf 2019</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/takeaways-from-rstudio-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/takeaways-from-rstudio-conf/</guid>
      <description>Cover photo by atmtxrstudio::conf 2019 is sadly over. I can honestly say it was one of the most interesting and educational conferences that I have been to, and I have come back with a long list of ideas which I want to get using right away! Here are some of the key points that I learned this week, with links to useful packages you may want to check out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Twitter Wordclouds in R</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/creating-twitter-wordclouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/creating-twitter-wordclouds/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished my PhD, and my supervisor, Patrick James, always described me as a “data monster” in reference to how much I enjoyed playing with data. He was a massive influence throughout my PhD, so I felt it was only appropriate to get him a data-related gift when I finished. To this effect, I made him a wordcloud of all his tweet history!
This blog post explains how we can interact with Twitter data in R using the rtweet (Kearney 2018) package, and convert this raw data into pretty visualisations using the wordcloud2 (Lang 2018) package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Launch of “A Village Inheritance&#34;</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/book-launch-of-a-village-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/book-launch-of-a-village-inheritance/</guid>
      <description>It was with great pleasure today that I was able to launch the book “A Village Inheritance” with my grandmonther, Clare Court, at Williton Library in Somerset. The event was a culmination of several years of hard work to get the book ready for publishing, and almost 50 years since the book was originally written, the book is available for all to enjoy!
We had no idea how many people would be interested in such an event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking from London to Basingstoke</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/walking-london-to-basingstoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/walking-london-to-basingstoke/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday 8th September 2017, I attempted to walk from London to Southampton as part of a charity fundraising event for Cameroon Catalyst. Unfortunately, I was unable to complete the whole route, as I had to withdraw due to injury at the 50 mile mark at Basingstoke, but it was an overall fantastic experience which I was proud to undertake.
This blog post aims to capture the enjoyment and pain of undertaking the challenge!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Plots with R</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/animated-plots-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/animated-plots-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists are blessed with a range of software tools which they can use to visualise results, and provide loads of great ways to present data which is equally informative and visually compelling. The increasing popularity of R ggplot2 (Wickham et al. 2018) has made many people familiar with static plots, but animated plots can be an effective way to communicate results, and there are few better examples than the use of them in the now famous TED talk by Hans Rosling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven flowcharts in R using DiagrammeR</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/flowcharts-in-r-using-diagrammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/flowcharts-in-r-using-diagrammer/</guid>
      <description>The old cliché goes that “A picture is worth a thousand words”. This may be overused, but I feel this is particularly relevant in data analysis, and we often use diagrams as tools to quickly communicate the results of our complex statistical models. However, whilst we often prioritise on explaining the results of the analysis, we are often less inclined to explain the stages used to reach the results to the same level of detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating blog to Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/migrating-to-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/migrating-to-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>I have been delaying it for a while, but I finally decided to move to blogdown. This post is designed to quickly capture my reasons for me changing, and highlight some of the features that may make you consider doing the same.
Note: this post does not intend to be a full tutorial on how to set up your blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping UK Local Political Data</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/mapping-uk-local-political-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/mapping-uk-local-political-data/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(eval=FALSE)For my PhD research, I needed to collect local political data for the UK. This article documents the data sources and procedure used to create a suitable dataset for my analysis. This provides a technical overview of the data. The R code used to create the analysis is available through GitHub here.
SetupR was used to run the analysis. The code uses a number of packages to process the data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing reports in RStudio: an introduction to RMarkdown</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/writing-reports-in-rstudio-an-introduction-to-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/writing-reports-in-rstudio-an-introduction-to-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>RMarkdown is a powerful tool for producing documents with embedded R code, allowing you to easily reproduce analysis and greatly simplify your data-driven workflow. It can be used to generate dynamic reports, presentations, journal papers, and even your thesis!
The presentation was designed to provide a whistle-stop tour of the benefits of RMarkdown, explaining the basic syntax to get started and highlighting some of the more advance things which you could use RMarkdown for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R for Geospatial Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/gis-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/gis-in-r/</guid>
      <description>IntroAlthough R is widely used for data processing and statistical modelling, it is less frequently known for its powers of handing Geospatial Data. This presentation is aimed to highlgiht why people may want to consider using R for their GIS, and highlight some of the benefits of using R in their analyses.
Why use R for GISThere are many benefits of using R for GIS, but to me the top three reasons would be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying key influences for planning acceptance of onshore wind turbines</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/wind-turbinesuccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/wind-turbinesuccess/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of presenting my work at the ECOS 2017 conference in San Diego, California. This page summarises the work and findings, with the research paper providing a more detailed decription.
Read the full paper
What is the problem?Wind energy provides a key opportunity for the UK government to meet decarbonisation targets. There is wide avaialbility of resource across the country, and onshore wind provides one of the most mature and cost-effective methods to supply renewable electricity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling Lands End to John O&#39;Groats</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/cycling-lands-end-to-john-o-groats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Michael Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/cycling-lands-end-to-john-o-groats/</guid>
      <description>Back in May 2016, a friend and I undertook one of the challenges which we had wanted to do for years and cycled the length of the United Kingdom from Land’s End to John O’ Groats. It was a fantastic experience and something I would love to do again one day. This blog provides a summary of our trip and aims to aid anyone who may be planning their own trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
