<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gis on Mikey Harper</title>
    <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/tags/gis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gis on Mikey Harper</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>m.harper@outlook.com (Mikey Harper)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>m.harper@outlook.com (Mikey Harper)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Mikey Harper</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mikeyharper.uk/tags/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R for Geospatial Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/gis-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Mikey Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/gis-in-r/</guid>
      <description>IntroAlthough R is widely used for data processing and statistical modelling, it is less frequently known for its powers of handing Geospatial Data. This presentation is aimed to highlgiht why people may want to consider using R for their GIS, and highlight some of the benefits of using R in their analyses.
Why use R for GISThere are many benefits of using R for GIS, but to me the top three reasons would be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying key influences for planning acceptance of onshore wind turbines</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/wind-turbinesuccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Mikey Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/wind-turbinesuccess/</guid>
      <description>I had the pleasure of presenting my work at the ECOS 2017 conference in San Diego, California. This page summarises the work and findings, with the research paper providing a more detailed decription.
Read the full paper
What is the problem?Wind energy provides a key opportunity for the UK government to meet decarbonisation targets. There is wide avaialbility of resource across the country, and onshore wind provides one of the most mature and cost-effective methods to supply renewable electricity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling Lands End to John O&#39;Groats</title>
      <link>https://mikeyharper.uk/cycling-lands-end-to-john-o-groats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>m.harper@outlook.com (Mikey Harper)</author>
      <guid>https://mikeyharper.uk/cycling-lands-end-to-john-o-groats/</guid>
      <description>Back in May 2016, a friend and I undertook one of the challenges which we had wanted to do for years and cycled the length of the United Kingdom from Land’s End to John O’ Groats. It was a fantastic experience and something I would love to do again one day. This blog provides a summary of our trip and aims to aid anyone who may be planning their own trip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>